# **Benjamin Sprenger**

Melbourne, Florida

Mobile: (203)-848-7528 | Email: <u>Beni.sprenger@hotmail.com</u> LinkedIn: <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/benjamin-sprenger</u>

Portfolio: <u>Bencoded.dev</u> Github: <u>github.com/azrazel95</u>

### Summary

As a full stack Web developer, the combination of technical and interpersonal skills that I bring to the table is unique, drawing from a background in hospitality and electrical work. Notable strengths include collaboration, leadership, mentoring, and attention to detail, and a drive to take on new challenges and push abilities to the next level. Growing up around IT support workers has provided me with a wealth of unorthodox experience that adds value to my perspective.

#### Technical skills

**Programming Languages and Frameworks:** HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Jquery, JS.Node, Express.js, React.JS, MySQL, MongoDB, Laravel, Java Spring boot, Python, Flask, C#, .net, DynamoDB, NoSql, Rest api's

**Software/Platforms:** Github, ChatGpt, mongoDB Compass, Heroku, Firebase, AWS, Linux, Vscode, Vercel, Heroku.

**Soft skills:** Understanding of api's, front end, back-end and content management systems, Ajax, accessibility, optimization and scalability of applications, agile development approaches

#### **Projects**

#### **Getoutdoorsfla.com**

- A group project created by 3 people, go aggregate many outdoors locations taking a grassroots driven approach. Utilises the Openweather API and Google Maps API.
- Responsible for Backend development and integration with the front end, as well as quality touches on the front end.
- HTML, Bootstrap, Mongodb, Graphql, React, Javascript, Node.js, Google fonts, ExpressJS, JWT, Mongoose, Axios, Jest.

#### Cloudyprophecies

- A simple yet elegant weather forecasting application. Utilises the openweather API.
- Responsible for conception, creation, design and deployment.
- Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, Moment.JS

## **Beard and Circus**

- A Tech/personal development blog utilising the MVC paradigm
- Responsible for conception, creation, design, deployment and upkeep.
- Mysql, Sequelize ORM, Express, CSS, Node.js, Bootstrap, Auth.js, Handlebars, Jass css, CSS, Babel

#### Experience

Electrician lead
All suncoast electric Inc.

2021-2022 Melbourne, Fl

Communication, Mentoring and Collaboration.

Working in a group of two with my apprentice, our team started vastly outpacing the rest of the company in both quality, speed and reliability, quickly becoming favourites among supervisors. By reducing the amount of trips the company has to make to fix issues, we cut costs by 25%.

# Pastry cook/Garde Manger Suntree Country Club

2017-2021 Suntree, FI

Organization, teamwork, working under pressure.

Cooking with a team of 12 before covid, producing high quality dishes was a passion. During covid this was reduced to a team of 2 including myself, thereby serving the same amount of people with a reduction in staffing of 73%.

# Food & Beverage Supervisor

2014-2016

The Como

Como, WA, Australia

Customer service, teamwork, working under pressure

Serving quality food and providing excellent service, the biggest accomplishment of this position was the change in attitude from the 7 servers and bartenders working under me and the improvement in service quality, we raised reviews on google maps from 2 stars to 4 within 6 months.

Retail assistant 2012-2014

Customer service, sales

Au-pair 2011-2012

## Education

Boot Camp Certificate: UCF, Orlando, Florida

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, and ReactJS.